<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Giraffe Facts</string>
    <string name="emoji_button">Show %s Fact</string>
    <string name="fact_source">Source:\n https://www.dosomething.org/us/facts/11-facts-about-giraffes</string>
    <string-array name="facts">
        <item> 🦒 Giraffes 🦒  are the tallest mammals on Earth. Their legs alone are taller than many humans—about 6 feet.
        </item>
        <item> 🦒 They can run as fast as 35 miles an hour over short distances, or cruise at 10 mph over longer
            distances.
        </item>
        <item> 🦒 A giraffe\'s neck is too short to reach the ground. As a result, it has to awkwardly spread its front legs
            or kneel to reach the ground for a drink of water.
        </item>
        <item> 🦒 Giraffes 🦒  only need to drink once every few days. Most of their water comes from all the plants they eat.
        </item>
        <item>🦒 Giraffes 🦒  spend most of their lives standing up; they even sleep and give birth standing up.</item>
        <item>The giraffe calf 🦒  can stand up and walk after about an hour and within a week, it starts to sample
            vegetation.
        </item>
        <item>Despite the females\’ attempts to stand over their calves during attacks by lions, spotted hyenas, leopards
            and African wild dogs (4), many calves are killed in their first few months.
        </item>
        <item>A giraffe\’s 🦒 spots are much like human fingerprints. No two individual giraffes have exactly the same
            pattern.
        </item>
        <item>Both male and female 🦒 giraffes 🦒 have two distinct, hair-covered horns called ossicones. Male giraffes use
            their horns to sometimes fight with other males.
        </item>
        <item> 🦒 Giraffes 🦒  only need 5 to 30 minutes of sleep in a 24-hour period! They often achieve that in quick naps
            that may last only a minute or two at a time.
        </item>
        <item>Whilst it was thought that 🦒 giraffes 🦒  did not make any sounds, this is now known to be untrue, as giraffes
            bellow, snort, hiss and make flute-like sounds, as well as low pitch noises beyond the range of human
            hearing.
        </item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
